Guide to the Nathaniel Tarn Papers, ca. 1939-2000 M1132
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Nathaniel Tarn papers
circa 1939-2014
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Tarn, Nathaniel
M1132
82.21 Linear Feet (186 manuscript boxes, 1 card box, 2 half boxes, 1 carton, 2 flat boxes, 4 VHS, 8 CDs, and 6 16mm film reels)
Scope and Content
The Nathaniel Tarn Papers are a particularly rich collection of materials, gathered over nearly sixty years of Tarn's highly-varied and well-respected career. The Papers include manuscripts of his published and unpublished poetry and prose, notebooks from his anthropological fieldwork, and correspondence with his personal friends, literary colleagues, and fellow anthropologists. Also included are audio-visual material and ephemera, as well as a complete set of his publications, in book as well as in periodical form. The collection arrived at Stanford accompanied by Tarn's own detailed listing of the contents, organized into three main series: Books and Manuscripts; Literary Correspondence; and, Anthropology and General Scholarship. To this end, Tarn's original organization and description is duplicated verbatim, with only a few minor editorial corrections changing the text. Unlisted and un-described materials found in the original accession, along with material added subsequently, have been inserted where deemed appropriate. Folder titles and descriptive text added during the processing of the Papers appear within brackets, typically with an explanatory statement. In addition, a fourth series was created for a separate listing of Audio-Visual Materials for tapes, compact disks, and film not originally listed or described by Tarn. Scope and content of the particular series follow below.
The 2006-2011 accessions consist of correspondence, notebooks, poems, diaries, calendars, daybooks, unpublished prose, books, journals, Avia drafts and related materials, Scandals in the House of Birds materials and typescript, miscellaneous drafts and proofs, cds, reel to reel film, Nathaniel Tarn's Ph.D. thesis, and some of Tarn's teaching materials.
Biography
Nathaniel Tarn was born in Paris, France in 1928. His childhood in Belgium was disrupted in 1939, when the threat of World War II prompted the family's removal to England. After graduating in history and English from King's College, Cambridge, Tarn studied anthropology, first at the Sorbonne and then as a Smith-Mundt-Fulbright Scholar at the University of Chicago, where he completed his doctoral degree based on fieldwork in the Mayan region of Guatemala. Further work in anthropology followed, with extensive research on Buddhist culture in Burma. Upon his return to England, Tarn received a teaching appointment to the London School of Economics, followed by a professorship at the University of London's School of Oriental and African Studies (SOAS). In addition to his expertise in the Highland Maya area and South East Asia, Tarn has also worked in the Himalayan region, China, Japan, Cuba, and Alaska.
After publishing his first volume of poetry Old Savage/Young City in 1964 and a celebrated translation of Pablo Neruda's The Heights of Macchu Picchu in 1966, Tarn decided to concentrate his energies on literature. He served as the General Editor of Cape Editions and the Founding Editor of Cape-Goliard Press in London from 1967 until 1969, then returned to the United States in 1970. Two years later he accepted a professorship in comparative literature at Rutgers, which he held until his retirement in 1985. Today he lives outside Santa Fe, New Mexico, remaining a creative and energetic force in modern poetry and the study of world literature.
As poet, essayist, translator, and editor, Tarn has published some twenty-five books, including an anthology of his collected essays in literary and cultural criticism, Views from the Weaving Mountain (1991). He is the recipient of numerous awards including the Guinness prize (1963), Wenner Gren fellowship (1978, 1980), Commonwealth of Pennsylvania fellowship (1984), and a Rockefeller Foundation fellowship.
Provenance
Purchased, 2000. Accessions purchased 01/2001, 05/2011, 08/2011, and 05/2015.
Access Restrictions
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Ethnology -- Guatemala; Poetry, modern -- 20th. century.; Anthropology.; American literature -- 20th century.; Tarn, Nathaniel
- Series 1. Books and Manuscripts
  Scope and Contents note
  Included are drafts of Tarn's full-length books, The Beautiful Contradictions, A Nowhere for Vallejo, Lyrics for the Bride of God, Atitlan/Alashka (with Janet Rodney), Seeing America First, and other titles. Drafts of his translations of Pablo Neruda's Heights of Macchu Picchu and shorter works for anthologies, Rabinal Achi from the Quiche Maya for Jerome Rothenberg's anthology Shaking the Pumpkin, and other works by Spanish and French poets. Transcripts, drafts, and copies of interviews of Tarn singularly, or in a group, as well as those conducted by Tarn can be found in this series, along with reviews of, and by, Tarn.
  - Juvenalia 1953-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Over 80 poems, mostly ts with some carbon and mimeographed copies, some with corrections; listed as rejects or possibles for Old savage/young city (1964)
  - Old savage/ young city - 64 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Original ts of some 50 plus pages with two pp of ms, corrected, proofs corrected by NT;corrected galleys with additions by NT; advanced issue review copy in wrappers. (Jonathan Cape, Random House)
  - Drafts: Old savage/ young city (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Original ts of several drafts, some corrected.
  - Thirteen to bled, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Original ts of some 20+ pages, corrected; NT's copy of booklet (a few copies homemade for distribution at Bled PEN Conference) with his notes.
  - Penguin modern poets no. 7 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    11 page photocopy with notes; second copy; NT is on pp. 77-111, sharing the book with J.Silkin and R.Murphy [Paperback sent to RBC]
  - Where Babylon ends: 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Original TSP of some 29 pages, corrected; another original typescript; 30 pp. of unpublished poems; wrappers'proof; illustrations; letters from Cape. (NT's first book with Cape Goliard & Richard Grossman)
  - The beautiful contradictions - 69 [1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Manuscript of research materials for the book of some 18 pages; 58 pp. carbon typescript of early draft with extensive corrections; 34 pp. transcript of another version; 30 pages of notes for the work; 13 pp. of corrected galleys; 40 pp. photocopy of a third version, corrected; 20 pp. of notes ms or ts and unused material; 13 pages of galleys; yet another fourth version, 33 pp. and a fifth, 16 pp.; other materials (Cape Goliard/Random House)
  - The beautiful contradictions - 69 [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Manuscript of research materials for the book of some 18 pages; 58 pp. C typescript of early draft with extensive corrections; 34 pp. transcript of another version; 30 pages of notes for the work; 13 pp. of corrected galleys; 40 pp. X of a third version, corrected; 20 pp. of notes H or TSP and unused material; 13 pages of galleys; yet another fourth version, 33 pp. and a fifth, 16 pp.; other materials (Cape Goliard/Random House)
  - NT: October - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Original 14 page carbon copy of ts; 2 sets of corrected galley proofs (Trigram Press in 3 variants)
  - NT: A nowhere for Vallejo - 1971 [1 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Small book containing 42 pages of manuscript; original ts of 40 pp., corrected; 69 pages of originalpaste-ups; 100 pp. of ts with copies and corrections; four sets of galleys, all corrected by NT; one version completely rejected (RandomHouse/Jonathan Cape)
  - NT: A nowhere for Vallejo - 1971 [2 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - NT: A nowhere for Vallejo - 1971 [3 of 4] (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - NT: A nowhere for Vallejo - 1971 [4 of 4] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - NT: The persephones, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    11 pp. corrected typescript; corrected proofs. (This small book illustrated by NT was published by Christopher Press and destroyed by fire.)
  - NT: LBG [Lyrics for the bride of God]: The artemesion - 73 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    original corrected ts of 20 pages; 40 pp. of early drafts and ms research notes; other material. (A part of Lyrics for the Bride of God published by Christopher Press)
  - NT: Lyrics for the bride of God-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    First draft given to New Directions: 35 page copy of transcript
  - NT: Lyrics for the bride of God (Box 3, Folder 5)
    final ts of approximately 125 pp. (New Directions/Jonathan Cape)
  - Lyrics for the bride of God [1 of 3] (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Some 375 pp. with additional materials of several drafts of several sections
  - Lyrics for the bride of God [2 of 3] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lyrics for the bride of God [3 of 3] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The house of leaves - 76 [1 of 4] (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Approximately 375 pages ts of original materials, many not used, unpublished.
  - The house of leaves - 76 [2 of 4] (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The house of leaves - 76 [3of 4] (Box 4, Folder 4)
    120 pp. corrected galley proofs (Black Sparrow Press); 3 original NT drawings made when drawings prepared for de luxe edition
  - The house of leaves - 76 [4 of 4] (Box 4, Folder 5)
    130 pp. photocopy of final version
  - The microcosm - 77 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    20 page photocopy (Membrane Press).
  - Birdscapes with seaside (Box 4, Folder 7)
    19 page clean ts [some carbon] plus unbound [proof]sheets (Black Sparrow Press)
  - NT/JR: Alashka -79 [1 of 7] (Box 4, Folder 8)
    A combined Selected Poems of NT (Atitlan) and a joint work with Janet Rodney (Alashka). 140 page photocopied ts; later version; carbon copy version; another version 150 pp. ts corrected; 90 pp. photocopied draft; 200 pp. photocopied proof with holograph corrections (Brillig Works Press, Boulder CO)
  - NT/JR: Alashka -79 [2 of 7] (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - NT/JR: Alashka -79 [3 of 7] (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - NT/JR: Alashka-79 [4 of 7] (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - NT/JR: Alashka -79 [5 of 7] (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - NT/JR: Alashka -79 [6 of 7] (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - NT/JR: Alashka -79 [7 of 7] (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - NT: AWG: The landsongs (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Photocopie ts; copy of the booklet (Shearsman Press, UK) [part of At the western gates]
  - NT: Weekends in Mexico - 1982 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    9 page ts; 13 draft pages with 2 pp. of notes; proofs (Oxus Press UK)
  - June snow - 1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    [original ms contained in booklet; corrected ts; clean ts]
  - June snow - 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    [Two booklets of newspaper clippings on Chinese culture]
  - NT: At the western gates - 85 [1 of 4] (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Original ms of some 30+ pages; original corrected ts of North Rim; original 80 pp. tsp drafts.
  - NT: At the western gates - 85, file 2 [2 of 4] (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Ts of setting copy annotated; photocopy of setting copy.
  - NT: At the western gates - 85, file 3 [3 of 4] (Box 6, Folder 4)
    2 sets of galleys (1 corrected).
  - NT: At the western gates - 85 [4 of 4] (Box 6, Folder 5)
    [Setting copy, few corrections]
  - NT: The desert mothers - 1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    25 page ts with corrections (Salt Works Press, Granada, MS); [several ts drafts of several poems are included]
  - NT: Palenque: new and selected poems - 1986 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    48 page galley proof (Oasis Press, London)
  - NT: Seeing America first - 1986, file 1 [1 of 2] (Box 7, Folder 2)
    7 page ms drafts of the "Rectangles"; some 200 pp. of ts drafts of various versions with handwritten corrections.
  - NT: Seeing America first - 1986, file 2 [1 of 3] (Box 7, Folder 3)
    2 sheets of ms notes on publication history of single poems; all following this point with notes and handwritten corrections, often heavily: some 85 pp. of TSP mostly of the "Narratives;" 9 pp. Conjunctions proof of "Four Poems;" & more 10 pp. Conjunctions proofs; 6 pp. Scripsi proofs; 4 pp. of Credences proof of Rectangles; 10 pp. ts of "Prefinal versions;" 24 pp. proofs on legal paper; 18 pp. ts of another version; 8 pp. original draft pages of "Persephone West" (10.9.86 - 10.14.86 in California); 17 pp. original ts draft & 2 ms pages (11.12.86 at Michael Davidson's house, Del Mar)
  - NT: Seeing America first - 1986, file 2 [2 of 3] (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - NT: Seeing America first - 1986, file 2 [3 of 3] (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - NT: Palenque: Seeing America first - 1986, file 3 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Some 75 pp. of early version of "Rectangles;" Coffee House Catalogue announcing book; neat photocopy of"Persephone West", more Conjunctions & Scripsi proofs; tls from Laura Chester for an anthology, with proofs and notes.
  - NT: Seeing America first -1986, file 4 [1 of 3] (Box 7, Folder 7)
    5 pp. "Narratives" proof for Conjunctions with Morrow/Tarn notes; some 200 pp. of further ts of various versions (Coffee House Press, Minneapolis).
  - NT: Seeing America first -1986, file 4 [2 of 3] (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - NT: Seeing America first -1986, file 4 [3 of 3] (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - NT: Seeing America first: proofs (Box 8, Folder 1)
    [Photocopied proof; correspondence; 2 slides]
  - NT: Seeing America first: corrected final ts (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Corrected final ts, photocopy sent to Coffeehouse
  - NT: Multitude of one - 80s, file 1 [1 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 3)
    3 page ms and 2 pp. photocopied drafts & notes; some 60 pp. ms notebook pages first drafts (10.1 - 19.86); 15 pp. of computer printout drafts; 30 further pp. of same; 16 pp. of same with excluded pieces; 25 pp. of early drafts with ms pages; 40 pp. of drafts with ms heavily corrected and another copy; 47 pp. computer printout of clean version.
  - NT: Multitude of one - 80s, file [2 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - NT: Multitude of one - 80s, file 1 [3 of 3] (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - NT: Multitude of one - 80s, file 2 [1 of 2] (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Full set of very fine Letterpress galleys from Grenfell Press with handwritten corrections (The GrenfellPress, New York).
  - NT: Multitude of one - 80s, file 2 [2 of 2] (Box 8, Folder 7)
    [Computer printout]
  - NT: Flying the body - 93 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    21 page clean computer printout of drafts; (Arundel Press, Los Angeles).
  - NT: Drafts, 1980s-1990s (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Mostly with handwritten corrections: 12 pp. computer printout of "The Mothers of Matagalpa" with Karl Young proof and 1990 program; 8 pp. computer printout of "Home;" 3 pp. Notus proof of "Ethnographies I;" 2 pp. ts of "P2EX87;" 10 pp. ms first drafts of "Indian Miniatures;" 14 pp. of rejected poems in ms & computer printout; some 80 pp. of miscellaneous poems in ts or ms.
  - NT: Drafts, 1990s (Box 9, Folder 2)
    All mostly with handwritten notes & handwritten corrections: 12 pp. computer printout of "A Calm on Flanders;" ms draft of "Saturn to the Venus City for Brad Morrow" & 24 pp. of drafts; 25 pp. of ts of "Red Banner's Whereabouts for Robert Kelly, with Conjunctions proofs; 12 pp. ts of "T(w)alks; 20 pp. ts of "Segalen travels with Gauguin for Lindsay Hill;" 10 pp. ts of "Breughel at Wien for Jerome Rothenberg;" 48 pp. ts for "The Army has Announced...;" with Trout Creek Press mock up of booklet; 12 pp. of "Bartok in Udaipur;" 15 pp. of NT translations from the Hungarian of Agnes Gergely; 24 pp. of miscellaneous materials.
  - NT: Views from the weaving mountain (American Poetry Books with UNM Press), file 1 [1 of 2] (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Some 300-400 pp. of computer printout, many with handwritten corrections, indices, tables of contents, some papers entirely in ms.
  - NT: Views from the weaving mountain (American Poetry Books with UNM Press), file 1 [2 of 2] (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - NT: Views from the weaving mountain (American Poetry Books with UNM Press), file 2 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Ms, photocopies, ts, and computer printouts, including a complete re-write of "Child as Father to Man in the American Uni-verse" which was combined with the separate "Dr.Jekyll, the Anmthropologist...Etc." for the volume Views.
  - NT: Views from the weaving mountain (American Poetry Books with UNM Press), file 3 [1 of 2] (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - NT: Views from the weaving mountain (American Poetry Books with UNM Press), file 3 [2 of 2] (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: page proofs (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Photocopied page proofs, front material, pp. 1-161
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: page proofs (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Photocopied page proofs, pp. 162-335 [end]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: prefinal proof (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Photocopied, pp. i-xiii, 1-168
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: prefinal proof (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Photocopied, pp. 169-end
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: final proof before Blues (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: Final, final proof before Blues (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: more proofs (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Incomplete set of proofs, photocopied, correspondence, front cover proofs
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: index (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Photocopied ts of several versions of the index
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: front material (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Several ts versions of preface, preliminary table of contents
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: other material [1 of 3] (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Photocopied ts and journal articles considered for weaving mountain
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: other material [2 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: other material [3 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Archaeology, elegy architecture: a poet's program for lyric [original title for weaving mountain]: preliminary material (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Photocopied ts and journal articles considered for book [1 of 2]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Archaeology, elegy architecture: a poet's program for lyric [original title for weaving mountain]: preliminary material (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Photocopied ts and journal articles considered for book [2 of 2]
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Views from the weaving mountain: miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Miscellaneous ts and photocopied material
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Selected poems, 1950-2000: ts [1 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Laser print copy of ts
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Selected poems, 1950-2000: ts [2 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Selected poems, 1950-2000: ts [3 of 3] (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. Selected poems, 1950-2000: proof (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Laser print copy of ts, plastic binder
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. The architextures: proof (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Laser print, photocopied, of page proofs, some handwritten corrections
  - Tarn, Nathaniel. The architextures: miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 4)
    publicity folders from Ninja Press, multiple copies
  - NT: Drafts for filing (Archive) (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Ms, ts material, some with handwritten corrections
  - NT: Autobiographies [1of 2] (Box 13, Folder 6)
    7 pp. "Towards Any Geography..." original ts and 3 pp. ms intention program for it; Conjunctions proof of "Dr. Jekyll..." with BM/NT notes with 17 pp original ts draft with heavy handwritten corrections & neat version; 24 pp. similar for "Child as Father..." (no proofs); 6 pp. original ts of "The Root of Exile" with heavy handwritten corrections; 12 pp. similar for "The Choral Voice" (3 drafts); 30 pp. early version of "Child" - "From the American Background to the Field of Action" with heavy handwritten corrections; some 30 pp. of notes; photocopy of Ron Sillman's "Realism" for Ironwood, Fall 1982.
  - NT: Autobiographies [2of 2] (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - NT: "Ethnographies" (Box 14, Folder 2)
    5 pp. original ts of "Willow (E I) for Edward Dorn" with heavy handwritten corrections & 2 other versions; 30 pp. of ts for other "Ethnographies"; 3 pp. mimeograph copy of NT's "Alaskan Artists of the World Unite" for Survival International 1976, with comments by other members.
  - NT: Poetics (Box 14, Folder 3)
    7 pp. original ts of "Hommage a Andre Breton" for the Nouvelle Revue Francaise (for which NT was forbidden to translate Andre Breton by the successor "Surrealists") with heavy handwritten corrections, clean version & notes (1967); some 50 pp. of original ts for "Archaeology, Elegy, Architecture" with several pp. of ms notes and reprint; 7 pp. ms notes for Smith College paper on Nishitani; 10 pp. original ms version of "Fresh Frozen Fenix: Notes on the Sublime etc...." for NLH [New Literary History] with clean versions and correspondence with editor Ralph Cohen; 4 pp. original ts of "Is there, currently, an American Poetry?" for Bartlett's American Poetry with handwritten corrections.
  - NT: "Pobiz" Montemora Issue (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Original ts of NT's piece with heavy handwritten corrections & clean version; materials on Eliot Weinberger's Pobiz issue of Montemora (EW claims NT invented the word "Pobiz"); & materials, mostly xerox, by EW, John Taggart, Carl Rakosi, G. & M. Oppen, Guy Davenport, Ron Johnson, Clayton Eshleman, M. DeGuy, Ed Sanders, etc. & Montemora materials.
  - NT: Reviews By (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Photocopy of NT's 2nd critical article on Alberto De Lacerda, for Critique; copy of London International Times, no. 34, (6.68) containing NT's "The Work Laid Before Us..."; proof of "Pop Culture" and original carbon copy of "Climbing Prague" & "Bomb Culture" for Lettres Nouvelles; original copy of "De l'Olympe a la Guinee" for Critique; original ts of "Science & the Shabby Curate of Poetry;" The Listener pages of "Pansies for Thought: on Levi-Strauss..." (5.11.67) [photocopied]; original copy of "Landscape Papers" for ABR [American Book Review?]; original copy for "Environment & Politics in the U.S." (unpublished); cutting of "Tajos" for NY Times [photocopied]; 12 pp. ts of piece on Primitive Art with handwritten notes, cuttings for NY Times (11.5.71) [photocopied]; 2 pp. piece on Wallace Stevens, 8 pp. ms piece on Tedlock's Popol Vuh with 6 pp. handwritten notes (12.29.85) and proofs, 10 pp. of reviews of John Digby s' Collage Book; Holbein and American Luminists (?unpublished) for Conjunctions.
  - NT: Reviews Of (Box 14, Folder 6)
    33 page photocopy of an unpublished ts by Kenneth White "A Propos of Old Savage" (6.65) and a copy with a handwritten note from KW. 17 pp. carbon copy of the same's "English Poetry 1950-69" signed (?unpublished); 5 pp. copy of the same's "Open Letter to All Hyperboreans", signed (?unpublished); Pat Callahan (U Notre Dame) photocopied ts on NT; fair collection of early and late cuttings of reviews and photocopies of cuttings.
  - NT: Interviews With [1 of 2] (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Jed Rasula & Mike Erwin original ts of unedited interview at New Hope, 9.23.73 with NT's handwritten corrections & handwritten notes, a carbon and 2 page als from JR; 37 pp. photocopy of LeeBartlett interview with LB's corrections (11.85) & a clean copy; 28 pp. photocopyof interview by same for UNM [University of New Mexico] Press book of interviews; 33 pp. photocopy of "verbatim transcript" interview by Molly McQuade (1992) for book on writers at U Chicago with NT's handwritten notes; 14 pp. edited version and 22 pp. revised version with NT's handwritten notes and 10 pp of als from MQ; 57 pp. computer printout of a 1995 interview with William Campbell (Naropa student) with NT's corrections & 48 pp. computer printout of final version with 2als from WC; photocopy of interview with L. Murphy (Rutgers Graduate) for a publication of his own (late 80s).